Rob Keleher

keleher.rob@gmail.com (+1) 610-306-4917

robkeleher.com linkedin.com/in/robert-keleher github.com/tryforceful

Astute senior full-stack software and web developer with an international mindset and a passion for elegant solutions both in code and in project leadership. Responsible for critical products with 16,000+ users at Bloomberg, LP. Experienced in coding environments comprised of 4 to 4,000 programmers. Passionate about Japanese language, culture, and foreign exchange with 2 years of experience living and working in Japan.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

WaniKani Userscripts

- Developed 3 userscripts for enhancing the user experience of the Japanese vocabulary web app WaniKani in the browser and in companion Android app "WK for WaniKani"
- Scripts provide aural talkback support for example sentences, mobile CSS restylings, and vocabulary info popover assistance during reviews and lessons

WORK EXPERIENCE

Think It First – *Frontend Web Developer*

Wayne, PA · 2019

- Implemented a dynamic consumer web app delivering aggregate buyer and listing data to dozens of real estate brokerages, generating 15x more sales leads and a 25% increase in signed listings
- Rearchitected former design as an embeddable Vue.js app allowing for customized interactivity, PDF generation, theming, and curated data content per individual brokerage
- Spearheaded in-office efficiency & optimization efforts in addition to implementation of coding best practices

JET Program – Senior High School Assistant Language Teacher (ALT)

Hakui, Ishikawa, Japan · 2016 – 2018

- Taught English as a foreign language & engaged in international cultural exchange with 400+ Japanese high school students
- Created and executed engaging ESL activities that fostered communication over 16 classes per week in 3 senior high schools
- Acted as an Area Leader for local JET participants, providing guidance in mental health and community resource referral
- Taught at local English cultural exchange workshops for elementary students and adults
- Composed monthly English outreach column for city magazine

Bloomberg, LP – Senior Financial Software Developer & Team Leader

New York City, NY • 2010 – 2016

- Oversaw a team of 4 to 6 junior & senior software developers in a high-paced, global corporate environment
- Owned & developed a full-stack ticketing & workflow management platform on the Bloomberg terminal for 16,000 employees
- Onboarded more than 35 internal departments to our platform, automating weeks of effort from their yearly workflows
- Personally designed and developed a scheduling interface used daily by 400+ operators and managers to track adequate global help desk coverage
- Encouraged and guided my team in Agile development methodologies as a certified Scrummaster
- Liaised directly with and brokered communication between clients, business teams, product stakeholders, and developers

Additional Roles

- Product Owner
- Project Manager
- Intern Mentor (4 years)
- · New Hire Mentor
- · Student Hackathon Mentor
- · Campus Recruiter

- Internal Recruiting Panelist
- · R&D Technical Knowledge Rep
- · Intern (1 year)

EDUCATION

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

C, C++, Java, SQL (MS SQL Server), JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Vue.js, HTML/XML, CSS, SASS, MS Office, UNIX, JIRA, Slack, Git, GitHub, Agile

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrummaster

Scrum/Agile Development, Feb 2016

Japanese Language Proficiency Test Level N3, Dec 2017

The Johns Hopkins University

Linguistics and Japanese

Baltimore, MD • 2007 - 2011 **B.S. Computer & Electrical Engineering** Minor in Math, additional focuses in